

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

A-152, New Ashok Nagar, Delhi - 110096

🛮 (+91) 9911194204 | 🖂 satyamyadav3@gmail.com | 🚱 satyamyadav.info | 👼 satyamyadav | in satyamyadav3 | 🔰 Satyam_yadav

Summary

I am a software development engineer with 2 years of experience in *Frontend Development* and *Javascript*, currently working at a healthcare technology company Innovaccer Inc. I am dedicated to deliver seamless user experiences along with architecting the resilient web applications.

Skills

Currently focusing Javascript - Design Patterns, Functional programming and reactive programming

Libraries - React, Redux **Frameworks** - Angular, Express **TDD** - Jest, Enzyme, Mocha, Chai

Relevant skills Packaging - Webpack, Gulp, Bower, Docker and Docker-compose

Version Control - Git

Automation - Gitlab CI, Circle CI

Release Management - NPM & Semver, Lerna

Also working with Heroku, Openshift, Google Cloud, Amazon Web Services, MongoDB, Redis Verdaccio, gatsby.

Work Experience

Innovaccer Inc.

Noida, Indi

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER - FRONTEND

Sep. 2016 - PRESENT

- I am working on InConnect with a team strength of ten which include two ui developers and provides omni-channel communication for better
 engagement of providers with patients through outreach, Two-way secure messaging and telehealth support.
- My key areas include understanding business requirements, planning, development, release management, staging deployments of two applications, a mobile web chat application and a SPA for bulk communication both running inside their docker environment over expressjs and using inhouse frameworks for shell rendering and react redux for spa.
- Developing framework agnostic design system using gatsbyjs, graphgl, sass, lerna and taking care of design inconsistency of the applications using scoped styles, css in js.
- I am actively involved in helping teams understanding BFF, micro frontend and modular application architecture we use, maintaining internal private npm registry using verdaccio and CI for smooth collaboration.
- My past roles include training team to write plugins and scripts for InGraph and migration of dashboards from legacy framework. Developing report automation tool for exporting analytical data in PDF format with data grids and visualizations which can be downloaded to browser, que for batch processes and written to filesystem or uploaded to a service using expressjs, redis, wkhtmltopdf, D3js.
- Developed package management tool for smooth collaboration and integration using git, git submodule, gulp and nodejs (child_process).

Freelance Delhi. India

 Web Developer
 Feb. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Worked on the social video micro blogging platform Franklyme, where I designed and developed embeddable responsive video widgets served
 over expressjs, dashboard to create, preview and get different widgets to be embedded in any web page by user.
- Some of highlights from my role are video-comment widgets (video version of disqus), web video recorder, hiring/audition video widgets wizard, hiripanel, admin/moderation panel.
- Rolled out my own framework on top of express.js, consuming rest APIs on server to build server rendered single page app That provides the look and feel of using modern single page app development frameworks like angularjs, ember etc. And with ability to retain easy and regular seo optimization as required by young business idea to gain traction through every channel And on the front-end side using regular jquery.
- Developed end to end web applications for initial evolution of the business idea for young startups like flatabout (now your yourquote.in), symptum.com.

Side Projects

stile

A FRAMEWORK AGNOSTIC DESIGN SYSTEM.

source

· Technology: Gatsbyjs.

MARCH 4, 2019 SATYAM YADAV - RESUME

json-form

FORM BUILDING FRAMEWORK WITH JSON CONFIGURATIONS, USING HTML FORMS.

source

• Technology: Express, NoseJS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Tabel, Mocha & chai.

postgres-express

A BOILERPLATE USING POSTGRESQL AND EXPRESS WITH TDD;

source

• Technology: Express, NoseJS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Tabel, Mocha & chai.

pwa-shell

AN ELEGANT APP SHELL FOR CLIENT SIDE PROGRESSIVE APPS.

source

• Technology: Service Worker, navigator, skeletopnpwa(dom api wrapper and router provider).

Learn-together

A PROJECT AND IDEA SHARING WEB PORTAL USING EXPRESSJS SERVER WITH POSTGRES.

source

• Technology: Expressjs, postgresql, redis, heroku, knexjs, jquery, bootstrap sass, gulp & bower.

Hexo-theme-stylesimple

A CUSTOM HEXO THEME USING CONFIGURABLE BOOTSTRAP BASED CSS LINKS AND PORTFOLIO PAGE.

source

• Technology: hexo, ejs, expressjs, sass, bootstrap

Education

Bachelor of Technology - 69.42%

Meerut, India

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2012 - 2016

Sir Chhotu Ram Institute of Engineering and Technology,

Chaudhary Charan Singh University Campus

Intermediate - 62.0%

Ballia India

SCIENCE 2009 - 2010

Gyankunj Academy

Highschool - 78.0%

Ballia, India

 SCIENCE
 2009 - 2010

St. Xavier's School

Open Learning

Bengaluru, India

JSF00 Oct. 2018

 Attained jsfoo a javascript conference covering the road ahead in JavaScript and the Web ecosystem, Functional programming Improving performance and UX, Building systems, tools and processes for teams, Case studies of Vue.js, GraphQL, ReasonML and other framework/language adoption.

Bengaluru India

GDD INDIA

Dec. 2017

• Attained Google Developers Day, India 2017, A two day event with Codelab and multiple learning sessions on development and technology like Data-driven PWA, web components, serverless computing, tensorflow and dialogflow.

Delhi, India

ARCHITECTING ON AWS

Jun. 2017

Completed one week AWS training on architecting on AWS which includes cloud computing, serverless architecture (lambda), efficient architecture and load balancing.

Meerut, India

FOSS July. 2013 - May. 2016

· Organised and workshops for linux and increasing Awareness towards FOSS in college.

March 4, 2019 Satyam Yadav - Resume 2